Akash Pattnaik 7978523242

akashpattnaik89@outlook.co

m

Summary:

- Skilled Java Developer with 10.4 years of experience in the full SDLC creating dynamic web applications.
- Updates functionality based on customer requirements to ensure excellent user experience.

Technologies Expert

Programming and Maintenance with Core JAVA/J2EE (JSP, Servlets, JDBC), JavaScript, Design Patterns, Hibernate Framework, JPA, Struts 1.x,Spring, Spring MVC & Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Spring Security, Oracle, Postgres, Maven, Apache Tomcat, JBoss, SVN, GitHub, Golang, Agile Methodology, Kafka, Core DNS, Java 8, Prometheus, Grafana & AWS Services.

Areas Of Expertise

- Project Management
- Strategic Planning & Execution
- Team Leadership & Development
- System Architecture & Engineering
- Application Design & Development
- Continuous Process Improvement

PROJECTS

- NagraVision- Nagra Scout
- CSR PORTAL -NISC (Client)
- VINGS Vidal Health TPA Pvt. Ltd (Client)
- Color Store Asian Paints (Client)
- Portal HR Module Lighthouse ERP ADCC Info cad Limited & Pix Transmissions Limited,
 Nagpur (Client)

Work Experience

Organisation : NagraVision India Pvt Ltd.

Role : Senior Software Engineer 2

Duration : Mar '23 till Jul '24

Tech stacks : Java 17, Spring boot, Spring Reactive / Web flux, Hibernate, JPA, Golang,

AWS, Postgres, Mongo DB,

Redis Cache, MQTT, Kafka,

Core DNS, Jira etc.

Roles & Responsibilities

- Working as Backend developer (Microservice based architecture)
- Participate in requirement analysis, Design discussions, Implementation, Code review and code deployment and Demo (toPO and other stack holders) phases.
- Participated in deployment of microservices to the EKS.
- Write Unit and Module test cases.
- Create branch and Prepare labs (pipelines) to test the changes on cloud (AWS)
- AWS Services- Lambda, EC2, S3, EKS, Cognito, RDS, Secret Manager, Cloud Watch, Code commit and Code Pipeline etc.
- Using Agile methodology

Organisation : Concentrix Catalyst (Formerly known as Prokarma Softech Pvt. Ltd.)

Role : Sr. Software Engineer

Duration : 12/2020 -02/2023

Location : Bangalore

Tech Stacks :Java.8, Springboot, Microservices, Spring JPA, Oracle, Swagger, JUnit, Cucumber,

Pact, Rest API

Roles & Responsibilities

• Demonstrable experience with Spring Framework (Spring Boot Preferred).

Strong experience in creating Restful web services.

Java testing Frameworks (JUnit, Mockito, Cucumber & Pact).

Organisation : RCS Tech LLP (Formerly known as RCS Technologies)

Role : Java Developer

Duration : 11/2017 - 11/2020,

Location :Bangalore

Tech Stacks :Java.7, Struts, JavaScript, JSP, Spring Core, Spring MVC, Oracle, Postgres SQL,

Putty, Jboss server, JUnit, Rest API

Roles & Responsibilities

- Supervise & lead team to ascertain the successful completion of the key projects of the company within budget & schedule.
- Developed well designed, efficient & testable code.
- Conducting software analysis, programming, testing & debugging.
- Refactored code & test suits to promote code reusable infrastructure.
- Developed Use interface using HTML & JSP.
- Involved in Analysis, Design, Development & Implementation of the application.

Organisation: Smart Edge Software Pvt. Ltd

Role : Software Engineer

Duration : 12/2013 - 11/2017,

Location : Bhubaneswar, Odisha

Tech Stacks : Java 5, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Servelets.

Roles & Responsibilities

• Utilize Java Enterprise, Java Bean, Java EE, AND Apache

- structs to develop fully automated client management systems for the efficient maintenance of client accounts.
- Enforce an innovative approach to improve the client's web reporting system, which effectively reduced the financial tracking analysis time by 50%.
- Oversee all phases of development of the new Java based vendor application system for the financial services industry from conceptualization & design to progress & deployment.

Education:

• B. Tech(2012) - Hi-Tech Institute of Technology-Bhubaneswar, Odisha